A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, S-Z FA394
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Stevens, David H.
  - 1948 January-June, Stevens, David Harrison; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Box 446, Reel M Ste 3, Frame 638)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on research and education in languages and foreign cultures, North American studies and on the betterment of libraries, museums, drama, film and radio. The diary includes a calendar/itinerary for trip to Mexico from January 22-31, 1948.
    Humanities; Language and languages; Drama; Guatemala; Mexico; Theater; Libraries; Linguistics; Translations; United States
  - 1948 July-December, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Stevens, David Harrison (Box 446, Reel M Ste 3, Frame 754)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on research and education in languages and foreign cultures, North American studies and on the betterment of libraries, museums, drama, film and radio. Includes Diaries on Great Britain July 1948.
    Ireland; Humanities; England; Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Music; Microfilms; Linguistics; Language and languages; United States; Translations; Africa; East Asia
  - 1949 January-April, Stevens, David Harrison; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Reel M Ste 3, Frame 890, Box 446)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on research and education in languages and foreign cultures, North American studies and on the betterment of libraries, museums, drama, film and radio. Stevens tours universities and libraries to survey Rockefeller Foundation Humanities grants. The diary includes notes on Stevens' visit to Europe from April 18 to June 12, 1949.
    Canada; Motion pictures; Austria; Microfilms; Humanities; Europe; England; Education; East Asia; United States; Drama; Radio
  - 1949 May-December, Stevens, David Harrison; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities. (Box 446, Reel M Ste 3, Frame 1,023)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of humanities focus on research and education in languages and foreign cultures, North American studies and on the betterment of libraries, museums, drama, film and radio. Relations with China are documented. The diary includes notes on Stevens' visit to Europe from April 18 to June 12, 1949.
    Ireland; Humanities; History; Germany; Scotland; Linguistics; Language and languages; England; China
- Stewart, Jane A.
  - 1962-1963 June (Box 447)
  - 1963 July-1964 May (Box 447)
  - 1964 June-1966 (Box 447)
- Stewart, John B.
  - 1953-1954 (Box 447)
  - 1955 (Box 447)
- Strode, George K.
  Europe; Brazil; Africa
  - 1927, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 1, Frame 1, Box 452, Box 448)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division who receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members. The dairy documents a sewage experimental station, a visit to Croatia to survey the opening of a school of public health and to examine local public health as well as updates from IHD fellows.
    Smallpox; Venereal diseases; Communicable diseases; Cholera; Epidemiology; Croatia; Tuberculosis; United States; Spain; Switzerland; Plague; Malaria; Sanitation; Public health; France; Europe; Italy; Hygiene
  - 1928 January-June, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Box 448, Reel M Str 1, Frame 105)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division who receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members. He interviews professionals in the field of public. The diary documents field studies in malaria, impressions of Belgium Colonial Health Services, contains Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division plans for 1928. Strode also travels to Germany and visits. The progress of IHD fellows is documented as well.
    England; Europe; Bulgaria; Communicable diseases; Austria; Belgium; Poland; Nursing; Netherlands; Ireland; Malaria; Hygiene; Infant -- Mortality; France; Germany; Public health; Sanitation; Tropical medicine; Tuberculosis; Venereal diseases
  - 1928 July-December, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 1, Frame 258, Box 448)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division who receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members. The dairy documents updates from IHD fellows and as well describes current year program initiatives.
    Typhoid fever; Tuberculosis; Denmark; Europe; Public health; Nursing; Norway; Malaria; Hygiene; Hookworm disease; Germany; France; Spain; Serbia; Sanitation
  - Index, 1929; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 448, Reel M Str 1, Frame 376)
    10 pages
    Yugoslavia; Venereal diseases; Ireland; Italy; Lithuania; Morocco; Norway; Nursing; Poland; Portugal; Public health; Romania; Sanitation; South America; Sweden; Tuberculosis; India; Spain; Hungary; Hygiene; Germany; Greece; Finland; France; Denmark; England; Communicable diseases; Czechoslovakia; Chile; China
  - 1929, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Box 448, Reel M Str 1, Frame 386)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division who receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members. He interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary surveys Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division programs in Europe. Strode also received IHD fellows updates.
    Ireland; Italy; China; Chile; Norway; Nursing; Lithuania; Morocco; Public health; Romania; Poland; Portugal; Sanitation; South America; Sweden; Tuberculosis; Venereal diseases; Yugoslavia; Hungary; Hygiene; India; Spain; Finland; France; Germany; Greece; Communicable diseases; Czechoslovakia; Denmark; England
  - Index, 1930; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 448, Reel M Str 1, Frame 567)
    12 pages.
    Public health
  - 1930, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 1, Frame 579, Box 448)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is to build up detailed knowledge of both public health problems and methods of dealing with them. He receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes IHD interests in Ireland, surveys Turkey's public health programs and various updates on public health nursing projects.
    Yellow fever; Venereal diseases; Yugoslavia; Switzerland; Spain; Turkey; Tuberculosis; Public health; Nursing; Sanitation; Romania; Bulgaria; Czechoslovakia; Norway; Austria; Germany; France; England; Denmark; Hygiene; Hungary; Holland (Netherlands: Province); Greece; Malaria; Italy
  - Index, 1931; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 1, Frame 702, Box 448)
    10 pages.
  - 1931, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 448, Reel M Str 1, Frame 721)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is to build up detailed knowledge of both public health problems and methods of dealing with them. He receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes International Health Division public health program activities in Poland, Denmark and Romania.
    Germany; France; Finland; England; Denmark; Czechoslovakia; Bulgaria; Austria; Nursing; Poland; Public health; Romania; Sanitation; Switzerland; Tuberculosis; United States; Norway; Greece; Holland (Netherlands: Province); Hungary; Hygiene
  - Index, 1932; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 448, Reel M Str 1, Frame 889)
    6 pages.
  - 1932, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Box 448, Reel M Str 1, Frame 895)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is to build up detailed knowledge of both public health problems and methods of dealing with them. He receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes a visit to Spain to discuss Rockefeller Foundation programs, a field research survey of malaria in Greece, a maternal mortality study in Germany and a survey of public health services in Portugal.
    Tuberculosis; Spain; Switzerland; Romania; Sanitation; Poland; Malaria; Mothers -- Mortality; Hygiene; Latvia; Greece; Hungary; France; Germany; Czechoslovakia; England; Austria; Belgium; Public health; Portugal
  - Index, 1933; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 2, Frame 1, Box 448)
    6 pages
  - 1933, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 2, Frame 15, Box 448)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is to build up detailed knowledge of both public health problems and methods of dealing with them. He receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes information on malaria field research in Greece and Bulgaria.
    Italy; Infant -- Mortality; Denmark; Croatia; France; England; Greece; Germany; Industrial hygiene; Hygiene; Romania; Public health; Nursing; Netherlands; Malaria; Albania; Austria; Bulgaria; Tuberculosis; Switzerland; Spain; Sanitation
  - Index, 1934; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Box 448, Reel M Str 2, Frame 140)
    20 pages.
  - 1934, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Reel M Str 2, Frame 160, Box 448)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is to build up detailed knowledge of both public health problems and methods of dealing with them. He receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes information on malaria in Spain and Portugal and an infant mortality study.
    Germany; France; England; Denmark; Industrial hygiene; Hygiene; Hungary; Greece; Public health; Romania; Sanitation; Spain; Bulgaria; Austria; Nursing; Portugal; Tuberculosis; Switzerland; Yugoslavia; Turkey; Italy; Malaria; Medicine, Preventive
  - Index, 1935; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 2, Frame 339, Box 448)
    17 pages.
  - 1935, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 2, Frame 356, Box 448)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The International Health Division carried out projects in malaria control, supported public health programs, gave aid to the organization or maintenance of essential services of state and national health departments and continued its contribution to the training of public health personnel as well as supports a fellowship program.
    Sweden; Sanitation; Spain; Nutrition; Palestine; Malaria; Nursing; Public health; Romania; Poland; Portugal; Yugoslavia; Greece; Germany; Hungary; Hookworm disease; Italy; Hygiene; Turkey; Switzerland; Austria; Lebanon; Czechoslovakia; Cyprus; Egypt; Denmark; France; England
  - Index, 1936; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 449, Reel M Str 2, Frame 528)
    14 pages.
  - 1936, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Reel M Str 2, Frame 542, Box 449)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is to build up detailed knowledge of both public health problems and methods of dealing with them. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes information on the scarlet fever project in Romania, a malaria study in Portugal and various surveys of public health programs in Europe.
    Greece; France; England; Czechoslovakia; Bulgaria; Austria; Albania; Public health; Portugal; Poland; Nursing; Italy; Hygiene; Hungary; Turkey; Scarlatina; Romania
  - Index, 1937; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Box 449, Reel M Str 2, Frame 698)
    13 pages.
  - 1937, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Reel M Str 2, Frame 711, Box 449)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is the control and investigation of specific diseases and to aid state and local health services. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes information on yellow fever field studies in Africa and malaria research in Italy.
    Uganda; Yellow fever; Sudan; Sweden; Malaria; Nursing; Africa; Kenya; Romania; Serbia; Palestine; Public health; Denmark; Egypt; England; France; Belgium; Bulgaria; Cyprus; Czechoslovakia; Greece; Hygiene; India; Italy
  - Index, January 1-June 24, 1938; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Box 449, Reel M Str 2, Frame 890)
  - Index, June 25-December 31, 1938; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Reel M Str 2, Frame 904, Box 449)
    7 pages.
  - 1938, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Reel M Str 2, Frame 911, Box 449)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an assistant director of the International Health Division working at the Paris Office. The focus of the International Health Division is the control and investigation of specific diseases and to aid state and local health services. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes impressions of public health in East Asia and India, and information on yellow fever in Africa.
    Singapore; Sanitation; United States; Yellow fever; Sweden; Switzerland; Tropical medicine; Uganda; Hawaii; Hong Kong; Hungary; Sudan; England; Epidemiology; Fiji; France; Cyprus; Communicable diseases; Egypt; Denmark; Hygiene; India; Cholera; American Samoa; Malaria; Medical education; Japan; Java; Public health; Romania; Nursing; Philippines
  - Index, 1939; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Reel M Str 3, Frame 1, Box 449)
    15 pages.
  - 1939, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Reel M Str 3, Frame 16, Box 449)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division working at the New York Office. The focus of the International Health Division is the control and investigation of specific diseases and to aid state and local health services. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary includes information on IHD program work in the Far East, fellowships and observations of Gambiae project in Brazil.
    Anopheles gambiae; Yellow fever; United States; Tuberculosis; Sanitation; Public health; Medical education; Malaria; Hygiene; Epidemiology; Entomology; Brazil
  - Index, 1940; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 3, Frame 226, Box 449)
  - 1940 January 1-June 26, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 449, Reel M Str 3, Frame 243)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division working at the New York Office. The International Health Division assists local and central health departments by aiding schools of hygiene, public health and nursing. The IHD has withdrawn many of its European programs due to World War II and focuses its effort in South America specifically for malaria field studies. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health.
    Yellow fever; Uruguay; Venezuela; Tuberculosis; United States; Argentina; Public health; Chile; Brazil; Ecuador; Dispensaries; Hygiene; Epidemiology; Infant -- Mortality; Industrial hygiene; Malaria; Medical education; Panama; Peru
  - 1940 June 27-December 31, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 3, Frame 364, Box 449)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division working at the New York Office. The International Health Division assists local and central health departments by aiding schools of hygiene, public health and nursing. The IHD has withdrawn many of its European programs due to World War II and focuses its effort in South America specifically for malaria field studies. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary contains information on a nursing school project in Madrid and Strode's travels in Portugal, Spain and France.
    Hygiene; France; Nutrition; Portugal; Public health; Refugees; Spain; Tuberculosis; United States; World War II
  - Index, 1941; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 3, Frame 526, Box 450)
    18 pages.
  - 1941, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 3, Frame 544, Box 450)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division working at Paris Office. The International Health Division assists local and central health departments by aiding schools of hygiene, public health and nursing. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary focuses on immediate wartime activities such as aiding public health services in Lisbon, Madrid and Marseilles. Strode travels to Russia to survey medical education and services, and focuses on nutrition programs.
    India; Medical education; Hawaii; Hygiene; England; France; Scotland; Australia; Spain; Singapore; United States; Switzerland; World War II; Wake Island; Sanitation; Russia; Public health; Portugal; Nutrition; Nursing
  - 1942 May 28-December 31, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Reel M Str 3, Frame 766, Box 450)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division (IHD). The IHD assists local and central health departments by aiding schools of hygiene, public health and nursing. The IHD focuses on health phases of the war effort, nutrition studies, research on various vaccines and field studies. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary details Latin American programs and a public health survey of northern Africa.
    Tropical medicine; United States; Nutrition; Nursing; Puerto Rico; Public health; Insect baits and repellents; Hygiene; Medical literature; Louse; Algeria; Vaccines; Ghana; Brazil; World War II; Yellow fever; American Red Cross
  - Index, 1942; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 450, Reel M Str 3, Frame 911)
    29 pages.
  - 1942 January 1-May 27, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Box 450, Reel M Str 3, Frame 941)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division (IHD). The IHD assists local and central health departments by aiding schools of hygiene, public health and nursing. The IHD focuses on health phases of the war effort, nutrition studies, research on various vaccines and field studies. Strode receives Rockefeller Foundation International Health Division program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary details a health survey of Iceland.
    Tropical medicine; Public health; Nutrition; Iceland; World War II; United States; Hygiene
  - Index, 1943; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Box 450, Reel M Str 4, Frame 1)
    26 page, includes index by country and general index
  - 1943, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Strode, George K. (Box 450, Reel M Str 4, Frame 27)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. George K. Strode is an associate director of the International Health Division (IHD). The IHD focus is to strengthen control of infectious diseases through field and laboratory work, and faces health emergencies inherent to World War II. Strode receives program updates from staff members and interviews professionals in the field of public health. The diary details a public health survey of northern Africa.
    Tuberculosis; Nutrition; Public health; Sanitation; Tropical medicine; Louse; Malaria; Milk; Morocco; Typhus fever; Vaccines; Yellow fever; Insecticides; Hygiene; Egypt; Algeria; American Red Cross
  - Index, 1944; Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Box 450, Reel M Str 4, Frame 227)
    27 pages, includes index by country and general index.
  - 1944 January-May, Strode, George K.; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division (Reel M Str 4, Frame 254, Box 450)